

Ashutosh Sawant

Project Engineer | AWS

Flat No. 9, E1 Building, State Bank Nagar, Panchwati, Pashan, Pune, Maharashtra, 411008, India

- **±** 28/06/1995
- ashusawant28@gmail.com
- **** 8446120117
- in Ashutosh Sawant
- AshuOO7

SKILLS

Linux Windows Administration

AWS

Docker

GitHub

Ienkins

Kubernetes

PKI

Virtualization

Bash Scripting

CERTIFICATIONS

Qualys Cloud Security Certificate Qualys

Deep Dive into Mobile Application Security Analysis Certificate

CDAC Hyderabad

INTERESTS

AWS Linux

Docker **Kubernetes**

LANGUAGES

Marathi **English** Hindi Expert Expert Expert

Project Engineer with 2+ years of experience working on Windows Server, Linux, Cloud, and Security. Advanced Knowledge of Bash Scripting, networking, and Linux. I can accurately justify my skill set and gain some proficiency.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Centre for Development of Advanced Computing (C-DAC), Pune (28/10/2021 - Present) **Project Engineer**

- My role is to look at the infrastructure of ACTS Group.
- System administration for Linux and Windows, as well as virtualization (VMWare, KVM).
- Setting up a Repository Server and a GitLab Server using Bash Scripting
- I set up server configurations of CENTOS 7 and BOSS operating systems by using bash scripting, and my work was also to monitor the servers for CCAT, AFCAT, and ICG
- Conducting technical training for Windows administration, Linux administration, Public Key Infrastructure (PKI), AWS, Docker and GitHub.
- Configuring the Tomcat Server and monitoring a website with Prometheus and
- Hosting a website on a Tomcat server, automating it with Jenkins, and pushing it to a GitHub repository.
- To use OpenSSL, a certificate was provided to the ACTS websites.

G.G. Patwardhan English Medium School, Ratnagiri

(15/06/2019 - 30/04/2020)

Maintenance Engineer and Teacher

- I joined as a Maintenance Engineer and teacher.
- I taught Maths and computer subjects to students and also worked as a maintenance engineer of TATA ClassEdge for this school.
- Linux server handling of TATA ClassEdge for this school.
- Monitoring and make monthly reports of the digital classroom for TATA ClassEdge.

Vision Institute, Ratnagiri

(09/10/2017 - 08/06/2019)

Corporate Trainer

- Conducted technical training for VMWare.
- Conducted technical training for Linux Administration.
- Conducted technical training for Windows Administration.
- Provided training on BASH scripting to candidates.

PROJECTS

Automation Hardening of Kubernetes Clustering

Bash shell scripting, Kubernetes, VM Ware Workstation 16, Centos 7

The project consists of the hardening of Kubernetes clustering with the help of the CIS Benchmark of Kubernetes 2020 using a bash script.

https://github.com/AshuOO7/e-ditiss_project

ACTS

Tomcat Server, Prometheus, Ubuntu and Grafana

The project consists of virtual website hosting with Tomcat Server and website monitoring with Prometheus and Grafana.

https://github.com/AshuOO7/ACTS-Project

EDUCATION

CDAC ACTS

(05/05/2021 -29/09/2021)

Post Graduation Diploma, IT Infrastructure, Systems and Security

• To understand the Concepts of Linux, Networking, Windows Administration, Data Centre Management, applications security implementation, Cloud and use various techniques for Ethical Hacking and Cyber Forensics

Dr. Babasaheb Ambedkar Technological University

(05/07/2013 - 08/06/2017)

B.Tech, Electronics and Telecommunication

6.75/10